A tune-filled animated extravaganza.
The Aristocats is a animation, comedy, family film
directed by Wolfgang Reitherman.
When Madame Adelaide Bonfamille leaves her fortune to Duchess and her children—Bonfamille’s beloved family of
cats—the butler plots to steal the money and kidnaps the legatees, leaving them out on a country road.
All seems lost until the wily Thomas O’Malley Cat and his
jazz-playing alley cats come to the aristocats’ rescue.
O'Malley (voice), played by Phil Harris.
Duchess (voice), played by Eva Gabor.
Roquefort (voice), played by Sterling Holloway.
Scat Cat (voice), played by Scatman Crothers.
Chinese Cat (voice), played by Paul Winchell.
English Cat (voice), played by Lord Tim Hudson.
The Aristocats is a 1970 American animated musical comedy film produced by Walt
Disney Productions and distributed by Buena Vista Distribution.
Directed by Wolfgang Reitherman, and based on a story by Tom McGowan and Tom Rowe, it was
the final Disney animated film released during studio co-founder Roy O.
Disney's tenure before his death on December 20, 1971.
Set in Paris, the plot follows a family of aristocratic cats who are set to
gain their mistress's fortune, much to the dismay of her butler.
Thrown into the countryside, the family is helped by a feral cat as
they attempt to return to their mistress's home.
The film stars the voices of Phil Harris, Eva Gabor, Hermione Baddeley, Dean
Clark, Sterling Holloway, Scatman Crothers, and Roddy Maude-Roxby.
The Aristocats project began as an original script for a two-part live-action episode for Walt Disney's
Wonderful World of Color, developed by McGowan, Rowe, and producer Harry Tytle starting in 1962.
Following two years of rewrites, Tytle suggested the project would be more suitable for an animated film,
which Disney temporarily shelved while The Jungle Book (1967) advanced into production.
When The Jungle Book was nearly complete, Walt Disney appointed Ken Anderson to develop preliminary work on The
Aristocats, making it the last film project to be personally approved by Walt before his death.
Longtime Disney collaborators Robert and Richard Sherman composed multiple songs
for the film, though only two made it in the finished product.
The Aristocats was released on December 24, 1970, to
generally positive reviews from film critics.
It was also a commercial success.
The film explores themes of paris, france, return, butler, cartoon, villain.
The tone is lighthearted.